hey guys somebody mentioned me in this
one it looks like a fun one we're given
three squares and some measurements and
it wants us to calculate the area of the
entire shape if you want to try it on
your own pause it right now because I'm
going to solve it in 3 2 1 it says
calculate the area of the shape I
believe it means it wants us to add up
all three of the squares so we just got
to figure out the area of each of the
squares and then add them all together
let's start with the largest Square in
the middle and let's give the sides a
length of X next let's focus on this
gray square and let's find one of its
side lengths since we know that this
entire height is equal to X and this
portion is 2 that'll leave x - 2 for the
yellow part and since this is a square
we know the bottom is also x - 2 and now
we're starting to fill out this 17 so we
have the x - 2 right here let's color
this blue for this portion now we just
got to find this last bit and then we
can set it all equal to 17 now for the
last part since the whole thing is X and
this piece is five that leaves x - 5 for
this piece and then once again it's a
square so the base is going to match the
height so this orange portion is x - 5
now we know that the yellow plus the
blue plus the orange will equal 17 so we
have x - 2 + x + x - 5 = 17 we can copy
it down and then combine like terms x +
x + x is 3x and -2 - 5 is -7 next we can
add 7 to both sides of the equation on
the left hand side we're left with 3x
and on the right hand side 17 + 7 is 24
and then we can divide both sides by 3
and that'll give us x = 8 now we know
this yellow X is equal to 8 this blue X
is equal to 8 and this orange x is equal
8 and we can simplify 8 - 2 is 6 and 8 -
5 is 3 so the area of this gray square
is 6 * 6 which is 36 the area of the
green square is 8 * 8 which is 64 and
the area of the brown square is 3 * 3
which is 9 and then 36 + 64 + 9 is 109
let's give it a label of cm squ and put
a box around it and that's the answer to
our question the area of this shape is
109 cm squared how exciting here's a
problem I'm planning on doing for the
next video it says solve for x and it's
XX - 4 + 1 = 4x - 4 and when I do post
it I'll try to put a link to the video
somewhere around here